John James Audubon Collection, 1788-1969: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
John James Audubon Collection
1788-1969
C0006
Princeton University Library. Special Collections. Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
3.3 linear feet 6 boxes 6 bound volumes
Audubon, John James, 1785-1851.
John James Audubon was a nineteenth century ornithologist, artist, and naturalist who published his illustrations of American birds and American quadrupeds. This collection includes several original manuscripts, transcripts of manuscripts, photostats, and other printed material related to Audubon.
John James Audubon was an ornithologist, artist, and naturalist. He was illegitimately born to a French slave trader and a Creole woman on April 26, 1785 in Les Cayes, Saint-Domingue in the West Indies, or what is now Haiti. Later in his childhood he moved to France, and when he was 18 moved to the United States. Audubon began to develop an interest in North American birds as he unsuccessfully moved through careers as a mine owner, a shopkeeper, and a businessman. Eventually settling into whatever odd jobs he could obtain, Audubon began seeking a printer in Europe to publish his drawings of American birds. In 1838, Audubon finally published his The Birds of America through publisher Robert Havell of London. From 1839 to his death on January 27, 1851, Audubon remained primarily in New York, working on another edition of his book and a new book, Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America, with his sons.
This collection consists of original manuscripts, photostats and transcripts of additional manuscripts, and printed material relating to Audubon, his life and work. Original manuscripts include several descriptions used in his Ornithological Biography (Edinburgh: A. Black, 1831-1839); manuscript descriptions to accompany plates 1-7, 10, 13-17, 19, 23, 25, 28, 31-32, 34, 36, 38, 40-41, and 45 in his Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America (New York: J. J. Audubon, 1845-1848); and over 50 letters by Audubon to his wife (Lucy Bakewell Audubon), his sons (John Woodhouse and Victor Gifford Audubon), Robert Havell (the English engraver of Birds of America), and others. In addition, there are original letters by Mrs. Audubon, his sons, John and Julia Bachman, members of the Bakewell family, and Francis Herrick.
More than 30 photostats and and 6 bound volumes of Howard Corning's transcripts extend the collection's coverage of Audubon's correspondence. Subject files of printed material include other Audubon exhibitions, Audubon's life in Florida, Robert Havell, portraits by Audubon, portraits of Audubon, and Mill Grove, Audubon's Pennsylvania estate. One box is completely devoted to Princeton's 1959 comprehensive Audubon exhibition, related correspondence and research material.
Collection is open for research use.
Letters purchased at Sotheby sale, July 2 1962. 10 additional letters purchased from Mike Papantonio. Drawings gifted in 1964/65. Transcripts gifted by Carl W. Buckheister.
No appraisal information is available.
Publications: Audubon's Ornithological Biography (Edinburgh: A. Black, 1831-1839) and Viviparous Quadrapeds of North America (New York: J. J. Audubon, 1845-1848); Letters of John James Audbon, edited by Howard Corning (1930).
The following sources were consulted during preparation of biographical note: Encyclopedia Britannica Online.
Audubon, John James, 1785-1851 -- Manuscripts.; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851 -- Exhibitions.; Audubon, Lucy Green Bakewell, 1788-1874.; Mammals -- United States -- 19th century.; Ornithology -- United States -- 19th century.; Artists -- United States -- 19th century.; Ornithologists -- United States -- 19th century.; Art history; History of science
- Series 1: Oversize Writings, dates not examined; 5 folders
  Consists of oversized writings of descriptions used in "Ornithological Biography," III and IV.
  Arranged by their order in the Ornithological Biography.
  - AMs [photostat], "The Wreckers of Florida," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 158-163, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - AMs [photostat], "Visits to & from Thomas Bewick," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 300-304, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - AMs [photostat], "A Tough Walk for a Youth," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 371-375, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - AMs, "Purple Gallinule," Ornithological Biography., IV, 37-42, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - AMs, "Glossy Ibis," Ornithological Biography., IV, 608-611, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Series 2: Oversize Letters, 1831 March 2-1840 April 5; 5 folders
  Consists primarily of correspondence to Robert Havell and Mrs. Audubon, 1831-1834.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Audubon, John James, 1831 March 2-1840 April 5; 5 folders
    - ALS to Robert Havell, with instructions for re-engraving legends, Edinburgh, 1831 March 2; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - ALS [photostat] to Robert Havell, Edinburgh, 1831 March 2; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Contains instructions for re-engraving legends. [Photocopy of B6 F6 above.]
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Manchester, 1834 September 5; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Liverpool, 1834 September 13-16; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - ALS to John Woodhouse Audubon, Washington, D.C., 1840 April 3-5; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Series 3: Ornithological Biography, dates not examined; 2 folders
  Consists of manuscripts of "Great Cormorant" and "Glossy Ibis."
  - AMs, "Great Cormorant," note, cf. Ornithological Biography. III, 458-469, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - AMs [photostat], "Glossy Ibis" revised version, Ornithological Biography. IV, 608-611, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    [Original in possession of Mrs. Wharton Sinkler, 631 East Garvers Lane, Philadelphia]
- Series 4: The Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America Vol. I, 1846; 5 folders
  These descriptive notes by J. J. Audubon, in his hand, were used by John Bachman in preparing the text for the Quadrupeds, first printed in three volumes (1846, 1851, 1854), to accompany the large folio plates (issued in three volumes 1845-1848; 150 plates in all). Comparison of these manuscripts with the printed text shows that Bachman edited the material supplied by Audubon, incorporating most of it in the final version, but with additions, omissions and other modifications. There are marginal notes by Victor G. Audubon and Bachman.
  This group of manuscripts comprises Audubon's notes for the following animals:
  Arranged by their order in The Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America Vol. I.
  - Quadrupeds, numbers 1-6, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - (1) "Common American Wild Cat", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 1 (text), I, 2-15.
    - (2) "Wood-Chuck", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 2 (text), I, 16-24.
    - (3) "Townsend's Rocky Mountain Hare", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 3, I, 25-30.
    - (4) "Florida Rat", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 4, I, 32-37.
    - (5) "Richardson's Columbian Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 5, I, 41-43.
    - (6) "American Cross Fox", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Plate 6, I, 45-54.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 7, 10, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - (1) "Carolina Grey Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 4)
      Plate 7, I, 55-63.
    - (2) "Common American Shrew Mole", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 4)
      Plate 10, I, 81-92.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 13-15, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - (1) "Musk-Rat", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Plate 13, I, 108-124.
    - (2) "Hudson's Bay Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Plate 14, I, 125-131.
    - (3) "Oregon Flying Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Plate 15, I, 132-135.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 16, 17, 19, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder
    - (1) "Canada Lynx", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 16, I, 136-144.
    - (2) "Cat Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 17, I, 145-150.
    - (3) "Soft-Haired Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 19 (text), I, 157-158.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 23, 28, 31, 32, 34, 36, 38, 40, 41, 45, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder
    - (1) "Mink" (fragment only), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 23 (text), I, 250-260.
    - (2) "Common Flying Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 28 (text), I, 216-222.
    - (3) "Collared Peccany", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 31, I, 233-241.
    - (4) "Polar Hare", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 32, I, 242-249.
    - (5) "Black Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 34, I, 261-264.
    - (6) "Canada Porcupine", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 36, I, 277-286.
    - (7) "Red-bellied Squirrel", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 38, I, 292-293.
    - (8) [American] "White-footed Mouse", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 40, I, 300-306.
    - (9) "Pennant's Marten", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 41, I, 307-315.
    - (10) "Wilson's Meadow Mouse", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Plate 45, I, 341-346.
  - Quadrupeds,4, No. 25, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - "Donny Squirrel", dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      Plate 25 (text), I, 199-201.
- Series 5: Letters Relating to Lucy Bakewell Audubon (Wife), 1788-1838; 12 folders
  Consists of correspondence from Lucy Bakewell Audubon and family members primarily to Miss Gifford.
  Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
  - Chronicle article re: these letters: "Mr. Audubon's Lucy" by H. C. Rice, Jr., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Audubon, Lucy Bakewell. ALsS to Miss (& Mrs.) Gifford, 1803-1838; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    (Note: Postscript: New Orleans, 11 April 1821, by J. J. Audubon on Lucy's letter of 1 April, 1821)
    [Purchased at Sotheby sale, 2 July 1962].
  - Audubon, Lucy Bakewell. ALsS to Miss (& Mrs.) Gifford, 1803-1838; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    [photostats of B1 F10 above]
  - Letters on STARK COLLECTION (TEXAS). Audubon - Bakewell Correspondence with Miss Gifford, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    [Description of Audubon Material in the Collection of H. J. Lutcher Stark, Orange, Texas]
  - Audubon, John James. ALS [photostat] to William Bakewell, La Gerbetiere, 1805 May 20; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    [photocopy of B2 F1 - also see note for B1 F14]
  - Bakewell, William. ALS [photostat] to Miss Gifford Fatland Ford (Penna.), 1805 July 19; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    (enclosing the above letter from J. J. Audubon 1805 May 20) (Original letter of William Bakewell not acquired by Princeton - original Audubon letter in B2 F1) [Sotheby Sale].
  - Gordon, Ann Bakewell. 2 ALsS to Mrs. Gifford, 1831 April 4; 1831 August 14; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    Dated 1831 April 4 and 1831 August 14 (mentioning her sister Mrs. Audubon); also: Miss M. A. Coltman to Mrs. Gifford 1838 (mention of letter from Mrs. Audubon) [Sotheby Sale]
  - Bakewell, Benjamin, et al. 28 ALsS to Miss Gifford, et al., 1788-1829; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    [18 from Sotheby Sale, 1962 + 10 additional letters not in sales catalogue purchased subsequently (1963) from Sotheby's].
  - Bakewell, William. 3 ALS to Miss Gifford, 1801-1808; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    [Sotheby Sale Catalogue - purchased subsequently from Sotheby - 1963].
  - Bakewell, Benjamin, et al. 28 ALsS to Miss Gifford, et al., 1788-1829; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    [photostats & transcripts of B1 F16].
  - Audubon, J. J. & Lucy. Letters to Benjamin Phillips & family, 1837; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    Typewritten manuscripts. [Originals in possession of Phillips descendants in England].
  - Gordon, Ann Bakewell., 1831; 1838; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    2 ALsS [photostats of B1 F15] to Miss Gifford, 1831; Miss M. A. Coltman to Mrs. G., 1838 (mention of Mrs. Audubon) [Sotheby Sale].
- Series 6: Letters, 1805 May 20-1918; 94 folders
  Consists of correspondence of J. J. Audubon and others, including original letters as well as photostats.
  This series is arranged into four subseries: Letters of J. J. Audubon (originals, filed by date), Letters of Others (originals), Letters of J. J. Audubon (Photostats), and Related Letters: Bachman et al (photostats).
  - Subseries 6A: Letters of J. J. Audubon (originals, filed by date, then transcripts), 1805 May 20-1855; 53 folders, 6 volumes
    Consists primarily of letters to Mrs. Audubon, with additional letters to Robert Havell, Victor Audubon, and Thomas McCulloch.
    - ALS to William Bakewell, La Gerbetiere, 1805 May 20 [Sotheby Sale], 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - ALS to Charles d'Orbigny, New York, 1807 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Re: Audubon, J. J. New Orleans, 1820 August 10: Deposition of Laverty repayment to Audubon & Bakewell for Shipment of tobacco 1817, 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Liverpool, 1826 September 3; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1826 December 9; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 May 15; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, London, 1827 June 20; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 November 25P.S. 1827 November 27-28, 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 December 21; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, London, 1828 November 2; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - ALS (fragment) to Victor G. Audubon, [London, ], 1829; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - ALS to Robert Havell, Edinburgh, 1831 March 26; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - ALS to Edward Everett, St. Augustine, East Florida, 1832 February 1; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Boston, 1833 May 4; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon (not same as preceding), Boston, 1833 May 4; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon. P.S. by John Woodhouse Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 14; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 18; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 19; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 22; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - ALS to Richard Harlan, M.D., Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 26; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 27; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 June 4; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon. P.S. by John Woodhouse Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 June 5-6; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Bras d'Or, Labrador, 1833 August 5; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - ALS to Victor G. Audubon, Charleston, S.C., 1833 November 9; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - ALS to R. Havell; also: proof for Plate 44, Birds of America, "Summer Red Bird.", Charleston, S.C., 1834 January 16; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - ALS to John Bachman, Baltimore, 1834 March 13; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - ALS to Robert Havell, New York, 1834 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - ALS to Victor G. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1834 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - ALS to Walter Horton Bentley, London, 1835 March 17; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - ALS to Messrs. Benjamin & John Gott, London, 1836 February 5; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - ALS to R. O. Anderson, London, 1836 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - ALS to Robert Havell, Charleston, 1836 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - ALS to Ward & Bell, Charleston, 1837 June 13; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - ALS to Thomas Nuttall, London, 1837 September 19; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1838 July 1; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - ALS (by Victor G. Audubon) to Mrs. Audubon, 1838 July 10; 1 folder (Folder 37)
      With postscript by John J. Audubon, Edinburgh.
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1838 August 1; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - ALS to Mrs. A. C. Alison, Edinburgh, 1838 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - ALS to John Calvert, Edinburgh, 1839 February 26; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - ALS to John W. Audubon, with postscript by Lucy Audubon, Edinburgh, 1839 May 23; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Audubon, Lucy. ALS to Victor G. & John W. Audubon, 1839 June 30-July 2; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - ALS to George Parkman, Lowell, Mass, 1840 August 26; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - ALS to Victor G. Audubon, Boston, 1840 September 14; 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - ALS to John Woodhouse Audubon, Boston, 1840 September 20; 1 folder (Folder 45)
    - ALS to F. L. Alden, New York, 1841 January 27; 1 folder (Folder 46)
    - ALS to Thomas McCulloch, Jr., New York, 1841 June 26; 1 folder (Folder 47)
    - ALS to Increase S. Smith, New York, 1841 August 15; 1 folder (Folder 48)
    - ALS to Col. J. J. Abert, New York, 1842 July 4; 1 folder (Folder 49)
    - ALS to Mrs. Audubon & Sons, Quebec, 1842 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 50)
    - ALS to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 2; 1 folder (Folder 51)
    - ALS to J. W. Audubon, with postscript by Victor G. Audubon, Minnie's Land, 1847 January 28; 1 folder (Folder 52)
    - Photographs of J. J. Audubon (ca. 1848) and of Mrs. J. J. (Lucy Bakewell) Audubon (ca. 1855), circa 1848; circa 1855; 1 folder (Folder 53)
    - Transcripts of Audubon's Letters, undated; 6 volumes
      Transcripts of Audubon lettets, edited by Howard Corning for his 1930 edition.
  - Subseries 6B: Letters of Others (originals), 1825 January 4-1918; 7 folders
    Consists of letters from Lucy Audubon, Victor Audubon, and John and Julia Bachman.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Audubon, Lucy (Mrs. John James). ALS to Prof. Joseph Henry, Washington Heights [N.Y.], 1863 August 14; 1 folder (Folder 54)
    - Audubon, Lucy (Mrs. John James), ALS to Mary Gaskell, 1836 May 10; 1 folder (Folder 54A)
      2 pp., with printed card of Victor G. Audubon (son).
    - Audubon, Victor G. ALS to J. T. Bowen, New York, 1847 April 14; 1 folder (Folder 55)
    - Audubon, Victor G. ALS to John Bohlem, New York, 1854 May 11; 1 folder (Folder 56)
    - Bachman, John. ALS to Joseph Bevan, Charleston, S.C., 1825 January 4; 1 folder (Folder 57)
    - Bachman, Julia R. ALS to Ruthven Deane, Columbia, S.C., 1903 January 10; 1 folder (Folder 58)
    - Herrick, Francis H. 3 ALsS to Edwin H. Johnson, Cleveland, 1918; 1 folder (Folder 59)
  - Subseries 6C: Letters of J. J. Audubon (Photostats), 1807 April 29-1843 June 13; 26 folders
    Consists of photostats of letters from J. J. Audubon, primarily to Victor Audubon, 1843.
    - ALS [photostat] to Charles d'Orbigny, New York, 1807 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 60)
      [photocopy of B2 F2].
    - ADS to Prather & Jacob, Promissory Note [photostat] Louisville, Kty, 1819 September 15; 1 folder (Folder 61)
      [Original in collection of Seymour Adelman, Philadelphia, Penn.].
    - 2 ALsS [photostats], to Baron de la Bouillerie (also, related memo), Paris, 1828 September 13; 1828 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 62)
      [Originals in the Archives Nationales, Paris].
    - ALS [photostat] to Robert Havell, Edinburgh, 1831 March 26; 1 folder (Folder 63)
      [photocopy of B2 F12].
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Charleston, S.C., 1833 November 9; 1 folder (Folder 64)
      [photocopy of B2 F25].
    - ALS [photostat] to Robert Havell, New York, 1834 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 65)
      [photocopy of B2 F28].
    - ALS [photostat] to W. H. Bentley, London, 1835 March 17; 1 folder (Folder 66)
      [photocopy of B2 F30].
    - ALS [photostat] to R. O. Anderson, London, 1836 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 67)
      [photocopy of B2 F32].
    - ALS [photostat] to Robert Havell, Charleston, S.C., 1836 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 68)
      [photocopy of B2 F33].
    - Receipt to Dr. S. G. Morton & Jos. P. Smith. Birds of America, undated; 1 folder (Folder 69)
      ADS [photostat]. N. p. 1 July 1837. [Original in the possession of Mr. Robert L. Walsh, Jr., 3424 Prospect St. NW, Washington, D.C.].
    - ALS [photostat] to John Calvert, Edinburgh, 1839 February 26; 1 folder (Folder 70)
      [photocopy of B2 F40].
    - ALS [photostat] to George Parkman, Lowell, Mass, 1840 August 26; 1 folder (Folder 71)
      [photocopy of B2 F43].
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Louisville, 1843 March 19-20; 1 folder (Folder 72)
      [From original in National Audubon Society, New York].
    - ALS [photostat, incomplete] to Mrs. Audubon, Ohio River, 1843 March 23; 1 folder (Folder 73)
      [Original in National Audubon Society, NY].
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 March 28; 1 folder (Folder 74)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 March 31; 1 folder (Folder 75)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 76)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 17; 1 folder (Folder 77)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 23; 1 folder (Folder 78)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, St. Charles, 1843 April 25; 1 folder (Folder 79)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Boonville, Mo, 1843 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 80)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Black Snake Hills, Mo, 1843 May 5; 1 folder (Folder 81)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Council Bluffs Mo. Territory, 1843 May 8; 1 folder (Folder 82)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Fort Fierre, 1843 June 1; 1 folder (Folder 83)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Fort Clark, 1843 June 6; 1 folder (Folder 84)
    - ALS [photostat] to Victor G. Audubon, Fort Union, 1843 June 13; 1 folder (Folder 85)
  - Subseries 6D: Related Letters: Bachman et al (photostats), 1825 January 4-1918 February; 8 folders
    Consists of photostats of letters primarily from Victor Audubon and John Bachman.
    - Audubon, Victor G. ALS [photostat] to J. T. Bowen, New York, 1847 April 14; 1 folder (Folder 86)
      [photocopy of B2 F55].
    - Audubon, Victor G. ALS [photostat] to John Bohlen, New York, 1854 May 11; 1 folder (Folder 87)
      [photocopy of B2 F56].
    - Letters V. G. A. & Lucy A. (xerox). Victor G. Audubon to S. F. Baird, 1850 November 21; 1 folder
      - Lucy Audubon to Joseph Henry, 1863 December 29; 1 item (Folder 88)
        [Original in Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.].
    - Bachman, John. ALS [photostat] to Joseph N. Bevan, Charleston, S.C., 1825 January 4; 1 folder (Folder 89)
      [photocopy of B2 F57].
    - Audubon, John James. Letters to Richard Harlan & J. K. Townsend, 1827-1838; 1 folder (Folder 90)
      TRANSCRIPTS of originals in Gilbert Collection, College of Physicians, Philadelphia.
    - Herrick, Francis Hobart. 3 ALsS [photostat] to Edw. H. Johnson, 1918 February; 1 folder (Folder 91)
      (re: Audubon's Quadrupeds)
      [photocopies of B2F59].
    - Bachman, John. 3 ALsS [photostats] to John K. Townsend, Charleston, S.C., 1838; 1842; 1 folder (Folder 92)
    - TRANSCRIPTS: J. J. Audubon to Mrs. C. C. Adams, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 93)
    - Lucy A. to same, 1864 January 27; portion of 1 folder (Folder 93)
      [Originals in Vodges Collection, Science Libr. Natural Hist. Museum, Balboa Pk., San Diego, California.]
- Series 7: J. J. Audubon, as Subject: Pamphlets, Clippings, etc., 1851-1964; 16 folders
  Consists of miscellaneous material such as pamphlets, exhibition catalogues, and portraits of J.J. Audubon.
  - Articles, Clippings, Pamphlets, etc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)